# Aida Urrutia M.

425.530.6745 | aidau85@outlook.com

# **PROFESSIONAL PROFILE**

Educated in Information Security and Digital Forensics with strong blend of education in Cisco networking combined with a proven work ethic. Skilled at managing projects from planning to implementation. Experienced at responding to unpredicted issues and taking the recommended corrective action to resolve the issue promptly.

Network Security | Cisco Switches & Routers Configuration | Cisco IOS | Cisco Packet Tracer | Cybersecurity Hardware and Software Installation | Digital Forensics | Report Writing | Virtual Machines | Ethical Hacking Microsoft Office Suite | Server 2016 | Wireshark | Hard Drive Imaging | Advanced Data Recovery

# **CERTIFICATIONS/CERTIFICATES**

Certified Ethical Hacker (CEH),

**EC Council** 

**Certified Digital Forensic Examiner,** 

**Cyber Security Academy** 

# **EDUCATION**

Associate of Technical Arts in Information Security and Digital Forensics, 2018

**Edmonds Community College, Lynnwood, WA** 

**BS in Electrical Engineering, 2008** 

University of Washington, Seattle, WA

# **CAREER HIGHLIGHTS**

Jamco America Inc. | Everett, WA

2014 - 2015 / 2019 - Present

## SEATS ELECTRICAL ENGINEER LEAD (2014 – 2015) / (2019 – PRESENT)

Led and directed a team of Engineers on electrical system and wire installations for premium class seats. Supported Engineers when issues arose and analyzed the impact on electrical and other departments. Analyzed and approved supplier technical documentation to ensure customer quality and requirements were met prior to submission. Witnessed environmental and electrical tests on parts installed into the seat.

Key Accomplishments:

- Ensured deliverables were met by delegating workloads and deadlines to Engineers.
- Prevented customer delays by coordinating with suppliers and other departments to meet deadlines.
- Recovered customer trust and met deadlines while being assigned to a late project that was behind.
- Taught Technicians how to pinpoint the root cause of failure enabling them to identify issues within an hour compared to a full day on their own.
- Created harnesses in two weeks to ensure a deadline was met where the previous designer had already spent three months working on them.
- Congratulated for the quality of a report wrote on testing the electrical system for load analyses.

**CONTINUED...** 

# Aida Urrrutia M.

Granite Falls, WA | 425.530.6745 | aidau85@outlook.com

# Boeing (Contractor through Chipton Ross) | Everett, WA

2015 - 2017

#### WIRE INSTALLATION ENGINEER III

Completed tasks on the Boeing 787 while focusing on wiring for the lavatories, class dividers, partitions, doorway liners, and video control station commodities. Reviewed wire installations, discussed deviations and improvements, analyzed and reviewed wire design installations, and signed off prior to releasing. Ensured proper views were displayed and aligned with the 3D model by reviewing and marketing up wire installation drawings.

Key Accomplishments:

- **Ensured design requirements were met and proposals were feasible** when developing the Boeing 777X wire routing installation for the new interior furnishing based on concept designs.
- Minimized delays by negotiating brackets and wire support installations to ensure proper harness provisions in commodities.
- Resolved factory tags and provided engineering design dispositions by working with Liaison Engineers and Manufacturing Engineers.

## Jamco America Inc. | Everett, WA

2010 - 2014

#### **SEATS ELECTRICAL ENGINEER III**

Advised the Project Supervisor if designs weren't feasible based on customer requests and recommended solutions. Created acceptance test procedures accounting for several seat configurations. Demonstrated the ability to manage a high amount of work by working on multiple seat programs for different aircraft manufacturers simultaneously. *Key Accomplishments:* 

- **Developed block diagrams** for integration into premium class seats and designed and routed electrical harnesses through the seat structure using CATIA electrical workbench.
- Trained and support technicians to perform electrical and IFE acceptance tests on completed seats.
- Identified root causes of electrical issues by working with technicians on the seat.
- Authored specification control documents outlining requirements for the supplier.

# Synrad Inc. | Mukilteo, WA

2009 - 2010

# **ELECTRONIC TEST TECHNICIAN**

Completed tasks on industrial CO2 lasers. Exacted corresponding procedures by assembling different series lasers. Tuned replacement driver boards to system specifications prior to shipment to the customer. *Key Accomplishments:* 

- Ensured functionality based on specifications by programming and testing PCB boards.
- **Troubleshot** non-working boards and reported problems to the design team.
- Reduced testing time by 50% by testing the laser using electronic testing equipment.

## Fluke Corp. | Everett, WA

Summer 2007

## **ELECTRONIC ASSEMBLER / MATERIAL HANDLER**

Assembled PCB boards and cables based on blueprint specifications and performed continuity tests using digital multimeters. Completed parts requisitions for Assemblers and located and entered parts into the internal database. Distributed parts to the proper destination. Created a custom-molded foam packaging using a foam-in-bag protective packaging machine.

**Key Accomplishments:** 

- Identified and resolved flaws and deficiencies.
- Acknowledged by the Supervisor as the department's best ever temp.